{
    "id": "Politica_97",
    "claim": "Companies from the richest conglomerates in the country, such as Sarmiento Angulo, Santodomingo, Gilinski and Squirilla Lülle, received subsidies from the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF) during the pandemic. According to Confecámaras, 80% of the largest companies in Colombia obtained the profit, compared to 9% of the Mipymes that accessed the PAEF. According to W Radio, companies in the “large” and “very large” categories received resources from the National Government's Formal Employment Support Programme, PAEF, which has subsidized the payroll of 139. 032 companies in Colombia to mitigate the crisis caused by the pandemic. 3. 012 companies with more than 200 employees received these grants between June and November 2020 - the hardest time of the pandemic, i.e. only 2% of all those supported. The bulk of subsidies were received by micro, small and medium-sized enterprises: 136. 000. Although small businesses were apparently the most benefited, if the focus of analysis is changed, as Confecameras pointed out, it is emphasized that in the country, there are registered, in total, 3. 851 large companies, which means that 80% of them had profits. In contrast, by November 2020, only 9% of Mipymes had acceded to PAEF, i.e. 136. 000 out of a total of 1.5 million in the country with between 10 and 200 employees. In May 2020, the National Government announced subsidies to companies, amounting to 40 per cent of a minimum payroll wage, provided that they had had a 20 per cent reduction in their turnover, in order to protect employment and cash flow of companies. However, despite the fact that there are 1 in the country. 503. 363 formal enterprises only 152. 621 officially requested payroll allowance and 139. 032 received it because they met the requirements, which means that the government helped, 91.1% of the companies that requested help. In total the government turned in those seven months 5 billion pesos: $2. 3 billion for 80% of large and very large companies and $2. 6 billion for 9% of mipymes. Among the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll are the Casa Editorial El Tiempo, the Hotel Estelar and the Concessionaria Via Andina, Coviandina, properties of the tycoon Luis Carlos Sarmiento Angulo. Other companies such as Jaime Gilinski Bacal, owner of products Yupi, Rimax Plastics, Hoteles Charleston Bogotá and Publications Week, as well as the Ardila Lulle Organization, the conglomerate of important companies such as Gaseos Postobon, Ingenio Incauca, Cristalería Peldar, Los Carros, Atletico Nacional, RCN Television, RCN Radio and Win Sports. Also obtained the profit the companies of Alejandro Santo Domingo heir of a business group that has important companies in media, in the field of commerce and tourism, and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country, and the companies of the Echavarría family, one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding. In December 2020, the PYM magazine noted that this year was difficult for companies because they had “reduced sales and demand for products; lower profitability; changes in consumption; fear of citizens; loss of jobs and lower wages; and difficulties in solving fixed costs; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries; limitations on international trade”, according to a survey conducted by Colombian businessmen, where 60 companies participated. But the majority managed to recover from the aid they received from the state. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.infobae.com",
    "date": "23/02/2021",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "Companies from the National Government in the country , such companies Angulo, Santodomingo, Gilinski and Squirilla Lülle, received subsidies from the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF) companies the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF) during the pandemic .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.infobae.com report on 23/02/2021?",
                    "answer": "Companies from the National Government in the country"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What companies received subsidies from the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF)?",
                    "score": 0.8663,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\tEmployment|nmod\tEmployment|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the National Government�s Formal Employment Support Program?",
                    "score": 0.7349,
                    "answers": "from the National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF ) companies the National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF )|prep\tFormal|nmod\tFormal Employment Support Program ( PAEF )|nmod\tthe National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF ) companies the National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF )|pobj\tFormal|compound\tthe National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF )|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Squirilla Lülle?",
                    "score": 0.6261,
                    "answers": "Squirilla|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to Confecámaras , 80% of the largest companies in the country obtained the profit, compared to 9% of the Mipymes that accessed the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF) payroll allowance .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that 80% of the largest companies in the country obtained the profit?",
                    "answer": "Confecámaras"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of companies in the country obtained the profit?",
                    "score": 0.8343,
                    "answers": "80|nummod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of Mipymes accessed the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program?",
                    "score": 0.8131,
                    "answers": "9 % of the Mipymes that accessed the National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF ) payroll allowance|pobj\tof the Mipymes that accessed the National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF ) payroll allowance|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the National Government�s Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF)?",
                    "score": 0.7339,
                    "answers": "Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF )|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Confecámaras?",
                    "score": 0.5931,
                    "answers": "to Confecámaras|prep\t80 % of the largest companies in the country|nsubj\tof the largest companies in the country|prep\tlargest|amod\tthe largest companies in the country|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "payroll allowance to W 139. 032 companies payroll allowance the “large139. 032 and “very large” categories received resources the National Government the National Government's Formal Employment Support Programme, PAEFthe National Government subsidized the payroll of 139.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.infobae.com report that payroll allowance to W 139. 032 companies received resources?",
                    "answer": "23/02/2021"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies received resources from the National Government's Formal Employment Support Programme?",
                    "answer": "032"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who subsidized the payroll of 139. 032 companies?",
                    "answer": "the National Government"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies received the National Government's Formal Employment Support Programme?",
                    "score": 0.7051,
                    "answers": "W 139 . 032 companies|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "032 companies in the country to mitigate the crisis caused by the pandemic .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies were in the country to mitigate the pandemic?",
                    "answer": "032"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies are in the country to mitigate the crisis caused by the pandemic?",
                    "score": 0.8263,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 032 companies in the country to mitigate the crisis caused by the pandemic|ROOT\tthat 032 companies in the country to mitigate the crisis caused by the pandemic|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies were in the country during the pandemic?",
                    "score": 0.8136,
                    "answers": "on 23/02/2021|prep\tto mitigate the crisis caused by the pandemic|relcl\tthe crisis caused by the pandemic|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What isinfobae.com?",
                    "score": 0.6185,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "012 companies with more than 200 employees the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many employees did the companies with the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia have?",
                    "answer": "more than 200 employees"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies have received government subsidies in Colombia?",
                    "score": 0.8223,
                    "answers": "in Colombia|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies did the government give subsidies to?",
                    "score": 0.8016,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tmore|amod\tthan|quantmod\tthe|det\tthat 012 companies with more than 200 employees the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|ccomp\tof the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia|prep\tthe|det\trichest|amod\tthe richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia|pobj\tor|cc\tentrepreneurs|conj\tthat|nsubj\tthat obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|relcl\tthe|det\tthe subsidy|dobj\tfrom the government|prep\tthe|det\tthe government|pobj\tto|aux\ttheir|poss\ttheir payroll|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies are there in Colombia?",
                    "score": 0.7966,
                    "answers": "012 companies with more than 200 employees|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many employees did the companies obtain from the government to maintain their payroll?",
                    "score": 0.7558,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 012 companies with more than 200 employees the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many employees does Infobae have?",
                    "score": 0.728,
                    "answers": "with more than 200 employees|prep\tmore than 200 employees|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll were received by micro, small and medium-sized enterprises: 136.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of enterprises received a subsidy from the Colombian government to maintain their payroll?",
                    "answer": "micro, small and medium-sized"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies did the government give subsidies to?",
                    "score": 0.7537,
                    "answers": "of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|prep\tthe richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What companies received subsidies from the government to maintain their payroll?",
                    "score": 0.7512,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tthe|det\tthe companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|nsubjpass\tthe|det\trichest|amod\tor|cc\tentrepreneurs|conj\tin Colombia|prep\tthat|nsubj\tthat obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|relcl\tthe|det\tfrom the government|prep\tthe|det\tto|aux\tto maintain their payroll|advcl\ttheir|poss\ttheir payroll|dobj\twere|auxpass\tthat the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll were received by micro , small and medium - sized enterprises|ccomp\t,|punct\tand|cc\t-|punct\tmedium - sized|conj\t:|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many small and medium-sized companies were received from the government?",
                    "score": 0.6805,
                    "answers": "small and medium - sized|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Although small businesses were apparently the most benefited, if the focus of analysis is changed, as Confecámaras pointed out, it is emphasized that in the country , there are registered, in total, 3. 851 large companies .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "In what country are there 3. 851 large companies registered?",
                    "answer": "the country"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many small businesses are registered in the country?",
                    "score": 0.7937,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that Although small businesses were apparently the most benefited , if the focus of analysis is changed , as Confecámaras pointed out , it is emphasized that in the country , there are registered , in total , 3 . 851 large companies|ROOT\tthat|mark\tsmall|amod\tsmall businesses|nsubjpass\twere apparently|auxpass\tapparently|advmod\tthe|det\tmost|advmod\tif|mark\tthe|det\tis|auxpass\tout|prt\tit|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\tthat Although small businesses were apparently the most benefited , if the focus of analysis is changed , as Confecámaras pointed out , it is emphasized that in the country , there are registered , in total , 3 . 851 large companies|ccomp\tthat|mark\tin the country|prep\tthe|det\tthe country|pobj\tregistered , in total ,|amod\tin total|prep\ttotal|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the impact of small businesses on small businesses?",
                    "score": 0.7859,
                    "answers": "Although small businesses were apparently the most benefited|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "3. 851 large companies , which means that 80% of 3. 851 large companies had profits.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies had profits on 23/02/2021?",
                    "answer": "3. 851 large companies"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many large companies have profits?",
                    "score": 0.8937,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\twww.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 3 . 851 large companies , which means that 80 % of 3 . 851 large companies had profits|ROOT\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tthat|mark\t3|nummod\t.|compound\t. 851|nummod\tlarge|amod\tthat 3 . 851 large companies , which means that 80 % of 3 . 851 large companies had profits|dobj\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\tthat|mark\t80 % of 3 . 851 large companies|nsubj\tof 3 . 851 large companies|prep\t3|nummod\t.|compound\t. 851|nummod\tlarge|amod\t3 . 851 large companies|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies have profits?",
                    "score": 0.8927,
                    "answers": "which means that 80 % of 3 . 851 large companies had profits|relcl\t80|nummod\tthat 80 % of 3 . 851 large companies had profits|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the profits of the 3.851 large companies?",
                    "score": 0.8578,
                    "answers": "profits|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In contrast, by November 2020 , only 9% of Mipymes had acceded to the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program (PAEF) , i.e. 136.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did only 9% of Mipymes accede to the National Government's Formal Employment Support Program?",
                    "answer": "November 2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of Mipymes acceded to the National Government�s Formal Employment Support Program in November 2020?",
                    "score": 0.8215,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that In contrast , by November 2020 , only 9 % of Mipymes had acceded to the National Government 's Formal Employment Support Program ( PAEF ) , i.e. 136|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "000 out of a total of 1.5 million in the country with between 10 and 200 employees.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many employees were in the country on 23/02/2021?",
                    "answer": "between 10 and 200"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many employees does Infobae.com have?",
                    "score": 0.775,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\twww.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 000 out of a total of 1.5 million in the country with between 10 and 200 employees|ROOT\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tthat 000 out of a total of 1.5 million in the country with between 10 and 200 employees|ccomp\tout of a total of 1.5 million|prep\tof a total of 1.5 million|prep\ta|det\ta total of 1.5 million|pobj\t1.5|compound\tthe|det\twith between 10 and 200 employees|prep\tbetween|quantmod\tand|cc\t200|conj\tbetween 10 and 200 employees|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people work for Infobae?",
                    "score": 0.7688,
                    "answers": "of 1.5 million|prep\tin the country|prep\tthe country|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In May 2020, the National Government announced subsidies to companies, amounting to 40 per cent of a minimum payroll wage, provided that they had had a 20 per cent reduction in their turnover, in order to protect employment and cash flow of companies.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did the National Government give subsidies to companies?",
                    "score": 0.8692,
                    "answers": "in order to protect employment and cash flow of companies|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What companies received subsidies from the National Government in May 2020?",
                    "score": 0.8211,
                    "answers": "of companies|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the National Government giving subsidies to companies?",
                    "score": 0.7701,
                    "answers": "employment and cash flow of companies|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the minimum payroll wage in May 2020?",
                    "score": 0.7405,
                    "answers": "to 40 per cent of a minimum payroll wage|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the minimum payroll wage?",
                    "score": 0.6976,
                    "answers": "on 23/02/2021|prep\tsubsidies to companies , amounting to 40 per cent of a minimum payroll wage|dobj\tamounting to 40 per cent of a minimum payroll wage|acl\t40 per cent of a minimum payroll wage|pobj\tof a minimum payroll wage|prep\tminimum|amod\tpayroll|compound\ta minimum payroll wage|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "However, despite the fact that there are 1 in the country.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people were in the country on 23/02/202?",
                    "answer": "1"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many states have 1 in the country?",
                    "score": 0.77,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that However , despite the fact that there are 1 in the country|ROOT\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tHowever|advmod\t,|punct\tthe|det\t1 in the country|attr\tin the country|prep\tthe|det\tthe country|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many states are in the country?",
                    "score": 0.7541,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat However , despite the fact that there are 1 in the country|prep\tthe fact that there are 1 in the country|pobj\tthat|mark\tthere|expl\tthat there are 1 in the country|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many countries are in the US?",
                    "score": 0.7128,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "363 formal enterprises only 152.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many formal enterprises did www.infobae.com report on 23/02/2021?",
                    "answer": "152"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many formal enterprises are there?",
                    "score": 0.8498,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\twww.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 363 formal enterprises only 152|ROOT\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tformal|amod\tthat 363 formal enterprises only 152|dobj\tonly|advmod\tonly 152|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "621 officially requested payroll allowance and 139.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people requested payroll allowance?",
                    "answer": "621"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people requested payroll allowance?",
                    "score": 0.667,
                    "answers": "that 621 officially requested payroll allowance and 139|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of how many requests for payroll allowance?",
                    "score": 0.6136,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\twww.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 621 officially requested payroll allowance and 139|ROOT\ton 23/02/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tofficially|advmod\tpayroll|compound\tpayroll allowance|dobj\tand|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "032 received it because they met the requirements, which means that the government helped, 91.1% of the companies that requested help.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How much of the companies that requested help did the government help?",
                    "answer": "91.1%"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of companies requested help from the government?",
                    "score": 0.8718,
                    "answers": "91.1|nummod\t91.1 % of the companies that requested help|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies received help from the federal government?",
                    "score": 0.8664,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\tthat|mark\tit|dobj\tbecause|mark\tthey|nsubj\tthe|det\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\tthat|mark\tthe|det\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthat|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies did the government help?",
                    "score": 0.8555,
                    "answers": "which means that the government helped ,|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In total the government turned in those seven months 5 billion pesos: $2.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what date did www.infobae.com report that the government turned in seven months of 5 billion pesos?",
                    "answer": "23/02/2021"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much money did the government spend on foreign aid in the last seven months?",
                    "score": 0.7942,
                    "answers": "those|det\t5|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "3 billion for 80% of large and very large companies and $2.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the amount of money reported by www.infobae.com on 23/02/2021?",
                    "answer": "$2"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of large companies use infobae?",
                    "score": 0.7304,
                    "answers": "80|nummod\tand|cc\tvery|advmod\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much money does Infobae make per year?",
                    "score": 0.7129,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj\twww.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that 3 billion for 80 % of large and very large companies and $ 2|ROOT\tthat|mark\t3|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the revenue of large and large companies?",
                    "score": 0.6718,
                    "answers": "large and very large companies|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "6 billion for 9% of mipymes.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of mipymes were reported by www.infobae.com on 23/02/2021?",
                    "answer": "9%"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of mipymes are made up of chemicals?",
                    "score": 0.8594,
                    "answers": "9 % of mipymes|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many mipymes are there?",
                    "score": 0.8185,
                    "answers": "that 6 billion for 9 % of mipymes|ccomp\tof mipymes|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the amount of mipymes in the world?",
                    "score": 0.7422,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t6|compound\t9|nummod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Among the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll are the Casa Editorial El Tiempo, the Hotel Estelar and the Concessionaria Via Andina, Coviandina, properties of the tycoon Luis Carlos Sarmiento Angulo.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the tycoon that owns the properties of Coviandina?",
                    "answer": "Luis Carlos Sarmiento Angulo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What companies have received subsidies from the government to maintain their payroll?",
                    "score": 0.8094,
                    "answers": "Among the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the government subsidies?",
                    "score": 0.7642,
                    "answers": "the companies of the richest economic groups or entrepreneurs in Colombia that obtained the subsidy from the government to maintain their payroll|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who owns the Casa Editorial El Tiempo?",
                    "score": 0.7156,
                    "answers": "Hotel|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the money that the companies received from the government for maintaining their payroll?",
                    "score": 0.6821,
                    "answers": "economic|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is the Concessionaria Via Andina located?",
                    "score": 0.6666,
                    "answers": "the Concessionaria Via Andina , Coviandina|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Other companies such as Jaime Gilinski Bacal, owner of products Yupi, Rimax Plastics, Hoteles Charleston Bogotá and Publications Week, as well as the Ardila Lulle Organization, the conglomerate of important companies such as Gaseos Postobon, Ingenio Incauca, Cristalería Peldar, Los Carros, Atletico Nacional, RCN Television, RCN Radio and Win Sports.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.infobae.com report that Other companies such as Jaime Gilinski Bacal, owner of products Yupi, Rimax Plastics, Hoteles Charleston Bogota and Publications Week were involved?",
                    "answer": "23/02/2021"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What companies does Gaseos Postobon and Ingenio Incauca own?",
                    "score": 0.8067,
                    "answers": "of important companies such as Gaseos Postobon , Ingenio Incauca , Cristalería Peldar , Los Carros , Atletico Nacional , RCN Television , RCN Radio and Win Sports|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What companies owns Yupi, Rimax Plastics and Hoteles Charleston Bogotá?",
                    "score": 0.7887,
                    "answers": "RCN Radio and Win Sports|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who owns Yupi and Rimax Plastics?",
                    "score": 0.7654,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tOther|amod\tthat Other companies such as Jaime Gilinski Bacal , owner of products Yupi , Rimax Plastics , Hoteles Charleston Bogotá and Publications Week , as well as the Ardila Lulle Organization , the conglomerate of important companies such as Gaseos Postobon , Ingenio Incauca , Cristalería Peldar , Los Carros , Atletico Nacional , RCN Television , RCN Radio and Win Sports|ccomp\tsuch|amod\tJaime|compound\t,|punct\t,|punct\tRimax Plastics , Hoteles Charleston Bogotá and Publications Week|conj\t,|punct\tand|cc\t,|punct\tas|advmod\twell|advmod\tthe|det\t,|punct\tthe|det\tsuch|amod\t,|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What companies are involved in the Ardila Lulle Organization?",
                    "score": 0.6998,
                    "answers": "RCN Television , RCN Radio and Win Sports|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the conglomerate of important companies like Gaseos Postobon, Ingenio Incauca, Atletico Nacional, RCN Radio and Win Sports?",
                    "score": 0.6351,
                    "answers": "Los Carros , Atletico Nacional , RCN Television , RCN Radio and Win Sports|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Also obtained the profit the companies of Alejandro Santo Domingo heir of a business group that has important companies in media, in the field of commerce and tourism, and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country, and the companies of the Echavarría family, one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia?",
                    "answer": "Warehouses Corona"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What companies does Echavarría family have shareholding in?",
                    "score": 0.8195,
                    "answers": "the companies of Alejandro Santo Domingo heir of a business group that has important companies in media , in the field of commerce and tourism , and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country , and the companies of the Echavarría family , one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|dobj\ta business group that has important companies in media , in the field of commerce and tourism , and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country , and the companies of the Echavarría family , one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|pobj\tthat has important companies in media , in the field of commerce and tourism , and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country , and the companies of the Echavarría family , one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|relcl\tthe Echavarría family , one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What companies does the Echavarría family have control over?",
                    "score": 0.809,
                    "answers": "Alejandro|compound\timportant companies in media , in the field of commerce and tourism|dobj\tin media , in the field of commerce and tourism|prep\tin the field of commerce and tourism|prep\tthe field of commerce and tourism|pobj\tcommerce and tourism|pobj\tone of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia|appos\tof the most important conglomerates of Antioquia|prep\tthe most important conglomerates of Antioquia|pobj\tits companies Warehouses Corona|pobj\tSodimac|compound\tSodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much money did the Echavarría family receive in investments?",
                    "score": 0.776,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com reported on 23/02/2021 that Also obtained the profit the companies of Alejandro Santo Domingo heir of a business group that has important companies in media , in the field of commerce and tourism , and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country , and the companies of the Echavarría family , one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the profit of the Echavarría family?",
                    "score": 0.6344,
                    "answers": "the profit|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the company that Echavarría family owns?",
                    "score": 0.599,
                    "answers": "Alejandro Santo Domingo heir of a business group that has important companies in media , in the field of commerce and tourism , and that also appears in the ranking of the men with the most money the country , and the companies of the Echavarría family , one of the most important conglomerates of Antioquia for its companies Warehouses Corona and for Sodimac – Homecenter and Falabella Colombia where they have shareholding|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In December 2020, the PYM magazine noted that this year was difficult for companies because they had “reduced sales and demand for products; lower profitability; changes in consumption; fear of citizens; loss of jobs and lower wages; and difficulties in solving fixed costs; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries; limitations on international trade”, according to a survey conducted by Colombian businessmen, where 60 companies participated.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies participated in a survey conducted by Colombian businessmen?",
                    "answer": "60"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many companies participated in the survey conducted by Cuban businessmen in December 2020?",
                    "score": 0.6387,
                    "answers": "to a survey conducted by Colombian businessmen , where 60 companies participated|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the demand for products in December 2020?",
                    "score": 0.6325,
                    "answers": "demand for products|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many companies closed businesses in December 2020?",
                    "score": 0.6279,
                    "answers": "that this year was difficult for companies because they had “ reduced sales and demand for products ; lower profitability ; changes in consumption ; fear of citizens ; loss of jobs and lower wages ; and difficulties in solving fixed costs ; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine ; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries ; limitations on international trade ”|ccomp\tbecause they had “ reduced sales and demand for products ; lower profitability ; changes in consumption ; fear of citizens ; loss of jobs and lower wages ; and difficulties in solving fixed costs ; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine ; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries ; limitations on international trade ”|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What were the reasons for the closure of businesses and suspension of contracts?",
                    "score": 0.5915,
                    "answers": "fear of citizens ; loss of jobs and lower wages ; and difficulties in solving fixed costs ; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine ; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the impact of the Ebola virus on companies?",
                    "score": 0.5889,
                    "answers": "reduced sales and demand for products ; lower profitability ; changes in consumption ; fear of citizens ; loss of jobs and lower wages ; and difficulties in solving fixed costs ; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine ; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries ; limitations on international trade|dobj\tlower profitability ; changes in consumption ; fear of citizens ; loss of jobs and lower wages ; and difficulties in solving fixed costs ; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine ; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries ; limitations on international trade|conj\tchanges in consumption ; fear of citizens ; loss of jobs and lower wages ; and difficulties in solving fixed costs ; closure of businesses and suspension of contracts due to quarantine ; shortage of raw materials and delays in deliveries|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But the majority managed to recover from the aid they received from the state.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what date did www.infobae.com report that the majority of the people recovered from the aid they received from the state?",
                    "answer": "23/02/2021"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much aid did Florida receive from the state?",
                    "score": 0.861,
                    "answers": "from the aid they received from the state|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the amount of aid given to the state of Florida in 2015?",
                    "score": 0.783,
                    "answers": "www.infobae.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the percentage of recoveries from the aid given from the state of Florida?",
                    "score": 0.7524,
                    "answers": "the|det\tthe majority|nsubj\tthe|det\tthey|nsubj\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the state do to recover the aid they received from the state?",
                    "score": 0.7312,
                    "answers": "the state|pobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}